Kyle Timins

161 Oxford Drive South Windsor, CT 06074 (860) 212-2254

July 18, 2013

Gregg Digenarro Position Here Travelers Ins Grove Street Hartford, Connecticut 06183

Dear Gregg Digenarro:

I would like to formally apply for the IT Early in Career program. As you are aware, I have a volume of experience with the company starting when I participated in the summer IT intern program for the last three years.

My IT experience gives me ability to apply technology to various areas. Some of the areas I have knowledge in includes security, networking, Linux, scripting, and learning new programs and processes. Please refer to my resume for examples demonstrating these skills.

i I appreciate your consideration and look forward to discussing this opportunity to advance my IT career at Travelers.

Sincerely yours,

Kyle Timins

encl: Resume

Kyle R. Timins

161 Oxford Drive South Windsor, CT 06074 (860) 212-2254 rzitex@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking an opportunity to participate in Travelers' IT Early in Career Program.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Software Engineering Vermont Technical College, Randolph Center, VT expected May 2014 Achievements:

- High School academic awards received in Math, Science, and Technology
- Recipient of Vermont Technical College four year Presidential Scholarship for excellence in high school academics

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: Perl 5, Java, HTML, Bash, Languages: Perl 5, Java, HTML, Bash, Languages: Operating Systems: GNU/Debian, Linux, Unix Certifications: Cisco CCNA Discovery 1-4

EXPERIENCE

IT Summer Intern

Jun '13 – Aug '13

Travelers Ins., Hartford, CT

OAI-SYS Department - Information - Systems Security

- Created Perl 5 scripts to perform metrics on compliancy
- Created and maintained database of Portable Media Exceptions
- · Created basic list of endpoint security.

IT Summer Intern

Jun '12 – Aug '12

Travelers Ins., Hartford, CT

OAI-SYS Department - Service Management

- Created Perl 5 scripts to increase efficiency and automation of Server Audits
- Performed Server Audit
- Headed XMatters add-on research to increase escalation efficiency
- Worked on N05/C03 patches for BMC TM ART monitoring system

IT Summer Intern

May '11 - Aug '11

Travelers Ins., Hartford, CT

OAI-SYS Department - Advanced Technologies

- Created Perl 5 scripts to increase efficiency and automation
- Fixed web applications to allow for cross-browser compatibility
 - Allowed custom tool tip pop-up to be used in non Internet Explorer browsers
 - Create copy from browser work-around for non Internet Explorer browsers
- Remotely reinstalled firewall device operating system and created written documentation
- Organized retired Cisco networking equipment for recycling

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Food Share volunteer, Varney Farm, South Windsor, CT

2008 - 2010

• Featured in 2010 Food Share monthly newsletter

EXTRA-	Server maintainer of VTC Adventurers Guild (Gaming Club)	2010 - 2012
CURRICULAR	Co-founder and President of VTCsec (Security Club)	2011 – 2013
ACTIVITIES	Competed in NYU Poly CSAW CTF	2011 – 2012
	Participated in CCSCNE Programming Competition	Apr 2013